# **ROSTISLAV VATOLIN**

+1 832 983 3965
vatolinrp@gmail.com
Houston, TX
https://www.linkedin.com/in/
rostislav-vatolin/

Expertise in: REST and SOAP APIs, microservice and monolith architectures

Tech stack: Java, Spring Framework, SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, JUnit, Mockito

Cloud providers: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Integrated with: Oracle DB, Azure Cosmos DB (Graph DB), Amazon Dynamo DB, Redis Cache, Gemfire Cache, Azure Service Bus, Apache Kafka

CI/CD: Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle

### **PROFILE**

Senior Software Engineer with more than **7 years** of Java development experience. Expertise in the development of **REST** and **SOAP** Java web services, PoC (proof of concept) solutions. Strong knowledge of AWS, GCP, and Azure cloud infrastructures. Propagator of Scrum and Kanban methodologies. Experience in **coaching** a group of students (15 students, 12 of which got a job as junior software engineer).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Energy domain, Houston, USA - 2020-Present

**Key-developer** role. Client maintains a heavy backend system of **microservices** to manage data in Oil and Gas industry. Migrated GCP based services to cloud agnostic solution with primary focus on deployment to Microsoft Azure infrastructure. Responsible for many **PoC** (proof of concept) work, ADRs (architecture decision records). Configured HPA (horizontal pod autoscaling) for services running on **Kubernetes** in Microsoft Azure Cloud. Refactored services to comply community standards, while contributing them to **open source**. Main stack: Java and Spring Framework. Unit and integration tests done using JUnit and Mockito.

## Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Telecommunication domain, Belarus - 2019-2020

Developer role. E-commerce project using **SAP Hybris** 1808 with Telco & Media Accelerator 1810. **Monolithic architecture**. Support and feature development using Java 8 and Spring framework. Tests using **JUnit** and **Mockito**. CI/CD done using Apache Ant and Jenkins. Deployment done in AWS Cloud environment.

# Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Heavy Building materials domain, Belarus - 2018-2019

Developer role. Developed new functionality using Java 8. Deployment carried over to **AWS Lambda**. Worked on persistence layer for integration with **AWS DynamoDB**. CI/CD done using Maven and Jenkins. Unit tests with JUnit and Mockito.

### Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Travel & Hospitality domain, Belarus - 2015-2018

Developer role. Created new functionality (REST APIs), enhanced existing in project's middleware area using Java 8, Spring framework, **Apache Camel**. Ensured enterprise systems integration with **Active MQ** and **Apache Kafka**. Carried deployments of OSGi bundles to on onpremise Redhat JBoss Fuse server. Worked on integration with **Oracle 11** database (created SQL queries), Gemfire cache. Tests done using: JUnit and Mockito. CI/CD done using Maven, Gradle, Jenkins.

### **EDUCATION**

Belarusian State University — Bachelor degree in Computer Science

### **INTERESTS**

Architecture, high-load systems, CI/CD, Clean code, tech literature.